http://www.banksafeonline.org.uk/privacy-and-cookie-policy

Skip to main content
Privacy PolicyFor the purposes of this privacy statement, "Payments Council", "we" "us" or "our" means Payments Council Ltd and their affiliates, successors and assigns. "you" and "your" means any natural or legal person who uses the website and each entity on whose behalf they act.Your privacy is very important to us and we take our privacy commitments to our users very seriously. We are notified under the Data Protection Act 1998 ("Act") and all information provided by you to us is dealt with in accordance with the Act. This Website Privacy Policy describes how Payments Council uses the information which it may collect on the website paymentscouncil.org.uk ("Site").This statement will be updated and amended from time to time so please check it on a regular basis.Please refer to our Website Terms and Conditions for details on the basis on which you may use the Site and its contents and the extent of our responsibility for such content.Personal InformationYou authorise us to store, use and otherwise process any personal information, including but not limited to your name, address, telephone number, company name and position and credit and debit card details, which personally identifies you ("Personal Information") to enable us to provide the services available through the Site in accordance with the terms of this Website Privacy Policy.If you provide us with any Personal Information, which is defined as Sensitive Data under the Act, then we will not disclose this to any third party for any reason without your consent.You must at all times ensure that the Personal Information you provide is accurate and complete and all registration details (where applicable) shall contain your real name, address and other requested details. You will notify us of any changes to these as soon as you are able so that we can update our records.You are solely responsible for your Personal Information and we may take any action with respect to your Personal Information we deem necessary or appropriate if we believe it may cause us to suffer any loss, liability or commercial damage.Any information provided by you in connection with any transaction regarding your credit or debit card numbers, expiry date and billing or delivery address will be used by us, or by others on our behalf, to process the transaction. These details will be stored either in a paper file or on a secure server and encrypted and may be used by us to facilitate and personalise future transactions with you.Whilst we will take all reasonable steps to protect your Personal Information, we cannot guarantee the security of any Personal Information you disclose online. You accept the inherent security implications of dealing on-line over the Internet and will not hold us responsible for any breach of security unless we have been negligent and then only to the limits set out in the Website Terms and Conditions.Why we collect Personal InformationYou are not obliged to give us any Personal Information in order to use the majority of our Site. We may, however, require certain Personal Information in order to offer you some services through our Site such as where you want to purchase products from us or request information or advice.The Personal Information is valuable in helping us to improve the design and range of the products and services provided by Payments Council. The use of your information will be kept to the minimum required in order for us to continue to provide the Site and our products and services.Payments Council will not sell, share with or transfer to third parties any information you provide except as set out in this privacy statement.What do we do with your Personal Information?You acknowledge and understand that Payments Council may use your Personal Information:to identify you;to administer, maintain and host the Site and related business;to administer any services we provide to you;to compile statistical analysis of the pages of the Site which you visit;to help us develop our business, products, services and the Site;to process, take payment for and deliver any orders you make with us for goods and services;for internal administration and/or analysis;to consider any applications or requests for information or advice made by you;if applicable, to consider your application for employment; andto comply with any legal or regulatory obligations.IP TrackingWe use IP addresses to analyse trends, administer the Site, track users' movements and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use, we also aggregate statistics, traffic patterns and related Site information. Such information is primarily used to provide you with an enhanced online experience. This information is generally not capable of personally identifying you. However where it does you have the right to require us to stop analysing it by contacting us at: media@paymentscouncil.org.uk.Third PartiesOther than to those third parties listed below, we will not disclose your Personal Information to any third party unless either we have your permission to do so, or we are, or consider ourselves to be, under a legal or regulatory obligation to do so. Your Personal Information may be disclosed to the following recipients, though we will use our reasonable endeavours to control the use of your Personal Information:Our third party service providers for the purposes of carrying out their services (including those used by us to complete your orders for products and/or services).Any person to whom we propose to transfer any of our rights and obligations under any agreement we have with you.Our professional advisers and external auditors.Any of our agents.HyperlinksThis Policy does not cover links within the Site to other third party websites. We are not responsible for the use of any Personal Information including without limitation cookies which you give directly to such third parties, or which third party websites may collect about you (using cookies or otherwise) while you visit pages hosted by them. Please refer to these third party websites' respective privacy policies for information about their use of your Personal Information and their use of cookies.Data ExportFor the purposes outlined in this Policy, we may send your Personal Information (which includes transfers to other parts of the Payments Council) internationally, including to countries outside the EEA (including those where our member banks are located). Please be aware that such countries may not have laws to protect your Personal Information.General InformationIf you wish to access or correct or delete any of your Personal Information as held by us, or if you have any questions or concerns about our Website Privacy Policy, Website Terms and Conditions or information we hold about you, contact us at: media@paymentscouncil.org.uk.Use of cookies by Bank Safe OnlineCookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site.Payments Council may collect information about your computer including your IP address, operating system and browser type for the purposes of, but not limited to system administration, aggregating information and statistical and auditing purposes.An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when connecting to the internet. This information does not identify you personally.Payments Council may obtain information about your general internet usage by using cookies. A cookie is a small piece of data or message that is sent from a web server to your browser and is stored on your hard drive. A cookie cannot read data from your hard disk or read cookie files created by other websites. Cookies help Payments Council to improve its websites and deliver a better and more personalised service.You may refuse to accept cookies or be alerted as to when a cookie is being sent by activating the relevant setting on your browser. If you choose not to accept cookies this Website may not function properly or may be considerably slower.The table below explains the cookies we use and why.CookieNamePurposeMore InformationBrowser Session CookiePHPSESSIDJSESSIONIDThis cookie is set by the website when a user visits the site and is an essential cookie for the operation of the websiteThis cookie does not display any identifiable or tracking information and is deleted when the user closes their browserGoogle Analytics_utma _utmb _utmc _utmzThese cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.Click here for an overview of privacy at GoogleSocial Sharingguest_idThese cookies are used to collect information about how visitors utilise the Twitter feature on the website.  No personal identifiable information is captured unless you are prompted and manually provide this (such as email) or are already logged onto your twitter account.Click here for an overview of privacy at Twitter.comMost web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit www.allaboutcookies.org.
